## KEITH B. BROWN

2 Mallard Place ~ South Windsor, CT 06074

860-436-4394 keithbbrown@att.net

### **SUMMARY**

Results-oriented Professional with extensive Operations, Quality Control, Project Management, and Financial Analysis experience in the Insurance and Nursing Home Industries. Holds license as Nursing Home Administrator. Core competencies include:

Internal Audit

Customer Service

Operations/Sales

Sarbanes-Oxley

Planning/ Budgeting

• Leading Teams

Compliance

• Data Analysis

Process Improvement

• Performance Reporting

Vendor Mgmt.

#### KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Increased regulatory compliance and consolidated reporting cycle by two days through more efficient processes.
- Built Access databases to improve the control environment and enhance data integrity.
- Improved control environments through implementation of new tools.
- Increased reporting clarity by restructuring report data and exhibits.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## ELLSWORTH MEDICAL, LLC, Windsor, CT

2011

#### **Product Manager**

- Providing in-service training on Safe Patient Handling products to Physical Therapists, CNAs, and Nursing staffs at Skilled Nursing Facilities
- Meets home accessibility needs through sales of floor and ceiling patient lift systems.
- Works with physician offices to streamline script process to provide Title XIX incontinence products for their patients.

# MASONICARE, INC., Wallingford, CT and Newtown, CT

2010 - 2011

### Administrator in Training

- Focused on all aspects of Skilled Nursing Care Administration
- Worked effectively with Director of Nursing and Medical Director to increase efficiency of ancillary services for long-term residents and short-term rehabilitation patients
- Assisted Social Services in obtaining customer feedback
- Worked with dining services and nutritionists to handle food ordering, storage needs, and delivery
- Assisted with vendor setup for housekeeping and plant operations

#### CONNECTICARE, INC., Farmington, CT

2008 - 2009

### Manager, Operational Quality Analysis

- Coordinated and reported Guarantee measures for employee benefit plan sponsors
- Delivered monthly results audit meetings for multiple departments within the Operations Division.
- Coordinated third-party audits from employer groups and Connecticut Department of Insurance.
- Assured payment compliance to authorizations and contractual obligations.
- Consolidated reporting cycle by two days through new, more efficient processes.
- Built Access databases to improve the control environment and enhance data integrity.
- Achieved customer satisfaction through customer focused HSA & HRA coordinated audits.

#### THE TRAVELERS COMPANIES, Hartford, CT

2007 - 2008

### Director, Design & Process Improvement, Construction Operations

- Managed analysis and reporting of monthly General Liability and Workers' Compensation results.
- Developed and maintain multiple Microsoft Access databases to analyze and disseminate data.

KEITH B. BROWN PAGE 2

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (Continued)

- Led Sarbanes-Oxley testing, documentation, and reporting for 20 construction field offices and approximately 150 operations control processes nationwide.
- Consolidated the reporting cycle by two days through new more efficient processes.
- Increased reporting clarity by restructuring report data and exhibits.
- Improved the control environment through implementation of new tools.

#### AETNA INC., Middletown, CT

2004 - 2006

#### Operational Accounting Manager, National Customer Operations

- Provided leadership to ensure full corporate and subsidiary compliance with the New York Health
  Care Reform Act (NYHCRA) through timely and accurate NY Pool payments averaging over \$13
  million per month.
- Performed trending analysis in support of reasonability auditing for state and federal claim surcharges.
- Streamlined reporting processes and increased regulatory compliance while providing management support and approval for numerous AIS projects and service requests.
- Drove a recalculation of claim payments for 2,500 customers over three years for Aetna's self-funded business to ensure state surcharge and Graduate Medical Education tax accuracy.
- Steered the tax reporting team responsible for preparation of 500,000 1099MISC forms for the Indemnity/PPO book of business and 80,000 W2 forms for Third Party Sick Pay customers.
- Worked closely with account management to fulfill case set-up needs for NYHCRA and Tax Reporting, generating a dramatic reduction in W2 reporting issues.

#### OXFORD HEALTH PLANS, INC., Trumbull, CT

2002 - 2004

#### Project Manager, Cost Containment & Recoveries (2003-2004)

- Drove audit and recovery teams of 22 employees reviewing \$165 million in inpatient implantable and high-cost drug claims with responsibility for staffing and implementation.
- Coordinated the Request for Proposal (RFP) process and managed relationship with OmniClaim, Inc. and Med Recovery Management, Inc.
- Tracked and reported hospital audit findings to executives at monthly contract governance meetings.
- Increased savings by 50% through highly cost-conscious vendor management.
- Designed and administered process to select 15,000 claims for submission for consideration under N.Y. Reg. 146, 4th Amendment (NY Individual and Small Group Risk Sharing Pools).
- Forged relationships with hospital contractors to develop claim analysis for contracting leverage.

### Project Manager, Claims Quality Management (2002-2003)

- Led an eight-person team while managing annual claim audits initiated by state regulatory agencies, hospitals, and employer groups through third-party administrators.
- Administered audits for delegated risk arrangements.
- Developed and implemented comprehensive audit program for hospital contract mapping.

#### **GENT FINANCIAL GROUP, West Hartford, CT**

2001 - 2002

#### Sales Representative

• Promoted and sold Life and Health policies

#### CIGNA HEALTHCARE, INC., Bloomfield, CT

1998 - 2001

#### Manager, Financial Analysis (2000-2001)

- Directed monthly updates and quarterly reporting for the Indemnity book of business across the Midwest and Southeast Regions, representing approximately 1,500 employer groups.
- Generated case profitability reports to regional underwriting.
- Analyzed and identified profit trends and escalated loss leading cases to underwriting.

### Sr. Auditor, CIGNA Internal Audit (1998-2000)

- Performed risk assessments and audits of various healthcare functions such as claim threshold audits, HIPAA readiness, pharmacy benefit management, and hospital facility management.
- Presented reports and analysis of audit results to all levels of the CIGNA management team.

KEITH B. BROWN PAGE 3

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (Continued)

# **EDUCATION & LICENSES**

ITHACA COLLEGE, Ithaca, NY B.S., Business Management, 1992
UNIV. OF HARTFORD, West Hartford, CT MBA., 2000
UNIV. OF CONNECTICUT, Storrs, CT Long Term Care Administration, 2010
LICENSED NURSING HOME ADMIN.
CT License # 001914